nginx it's like a gateway that stands between the internet and your back-end
nginx像一个网关，位于互联网和后端基础架构之间
infrastructure when you visit a web app the first place
当您访问 Web 应用程序时您的请求首先会
your request will go is to a web server its job is to look at the requested
发送到 Web 服务器，它的任务是查看请求的资源
resource and determine where to find it on the server then send it back
并确定在服务器哪个地方可以找到它
as the response in fact if you open up the network tab in chrome dev tools
然后将其作为响应返回，事实上如果您现在在 chrome 开发工具中打开网络选项卡
right now you can look at the server header on any
您可以查看任何服务器上的响应上请求头
response and there's a good chance it'll be nginx
它很有可能就是nginx
it's extremely popular with high traffic sites because it can handle more than 10
它在高并发站点非常受欢迎
000 simultaneous connections with its event driven architecture
因为它可以通过事件驱动架构，能同时处理超过 10,000 个连接
it's also commonly used as a reverse proxy where it acts as a traffic light
它通常也用作反向代理，它充当信号灯将负载
to distribute the load to multiple backend servers while also providing
分配到多个后端服务器，同时在大多数情况下
security and caching for better performance in
还提供安全性和缓存以便获得更好的性能
most cases it'll be installed on a linux server with the configuration file being
将它安装在 linux服务器上，配置文件位于 etc目录中
found in the etc directory you customize the behavior of
您可以通过定义指令自定义服务器的行为
your server by defining directives a directive is just a key value pair or
指令只是一个键值对，如果后面跟着
if followed by braces it's known as a context which itself holds more
大括号它被称为上下文
directives in the global context we might want to
它本身在全局上下文中包含很多指令
specify things like a username and where to save our error logs but
我们或许想要指定用户名和保存错误日志的位置
most of your configuration will likely be done in the http context
但您的大部分配置可能会在 http 上下文中完成
now one of the most important roles of nginx is to serve out static content
现在nginx 最重要的角色之一是提供静态内容
like images and html we can handle that in
像图像和 html，我们可以在 http 上下文中处理它
the http context where we'll define one or more servers
我们将定义一个或多个服务器
each server is distinguished by the port that it listens to nginx will keep track
每个服务器由端口区分，nginx监听器将跟踪对服务器的每个请求
of every request to the server which you can write to an access log the
可以将其写入访问日志中
most important thing though is to tell the server where to find the raw files
但最重要的是告诉服务器在哪里可以找到
which we do in the location context now when a user navigates to our domain
我们现在配置上下文中执行的原始文件，当用户访问到我们的网站时
it knows where to find the html on the file system and we might want to
它知道在文件系统上的哪个位置可以找到html
set up a second location to match any image pattern to the images
我们可能希望设置第二个位置以将任何图像模式与图像目录匹配
directory other common things you might handle in your server config
您可能会在您的文件系统中处理其他常见的服务器配置相的关操作
include ssl certificates rewrites and routing to a proxy server when i replace
包括 ssl 证书重写和路由代理服务器
root with proxy pass i can point to a completely different
当我用代理通行证替换 root时，我可以创建一个反向代理
server on the internet what we've created is a reverse proxy that can
指向互联网上完全不同的服务器
handle caching anonymity and load balancing this has
可以处理缓存匿名和负载均衡
been nginx in 100 seconds hit the like button if you want to see
这就是100秒对nginx的简单介绍
more short videos like this thanks for watching
更多这样的短视频敬请期待
and i will see you in the next one
下次见